Daniel

Sánchez Romo

Software Engineer

+52 (33) 33198928 contacto@daniromo.me https://vitae.daniromo.me

Tlajomulco de Zúñiga, Jalisco

About me

I've been working in the enterprise software industry for about 5 years now even though I started coding almost 10 years ago. The aspect I like the most about programming is learning. Whether it might be a new technology or best practices for the tools I already know, the implicit growth that I get from it drives my motivation to build better products everyday. I'm also really into ui design.

Skills

Front End Development using Angular, Ionic (Typescript)

Back End Development using NodeJS & Spring Boot (Typescript, Java)

Database Administration for PostgreSQL, MariaDB & MongoDB

Extensive GNU/Linux Knowledge as well as AWS & other cloud platforms

MVC Patterns, OOP Knowledge & SOLID Principles

Version Control and Collaborative Workflows using Git

Capacitor & Cordova for hybrid mobile applications development

Experience

Norfolk Southern, Hybrid Mobile Applications Developer - Contractor through Aptonet AUGUST 2022-CURRENT, REMOTE

UI Development

Enterprise grade hybrid mobile applications development using Angular & Ionic

Leveraged capacitor and cordova plugins to use native mobile api's

Migrated legacy applications into modern technologies

Created SQLite databases to make big datasets performant on mobile

Managed application state using redux libraries such as NGRX & NGXS

Implemented enterprise grade OAuth into several hybrid applications

Deployed applications to vendor stores and offered support for approximately six thousand users

TATA Consultancy Services, Software Engineer

FEBRUARY 2022-AUGUST 2022, GUADALAJARA

UI Development

Enterprise grade frontend development using Angular

Managed application state using NgRx Store (redux pattern)

Followed micro frontend architecture to develop web applications

Actively participated in agile ceremonies

Developed and enhanced reusable components used throughout teams

Mentored junior Angular resources with knowledge transfer sessions as well as code reviewing

Followed best practices with security and performance in mind

Worked with test driven UI development to ensure quality expectations

WAppVR, JR Developer

AUGUST 2020-FEBRUARY 2022, GUADALAJARA

Full Stack Developer

Built robust REST APIs using Node.js (with and without Typescript)

Deployed and managed multiple applications to AWS and Digital Ocean

Safely transformed millions of records in production databases

Promoted the use of agile methodology company wide

Wrote manuals to help with the training of fellow developers

Assisted in frontend development using Angular

Education

Universidad Tecnológica de Jalisco, Técnico Superior Universitario

GUADALAJARA, JALISCO, MÉXICO

Tecnologías de la Información área Desarrollo de Software Multiplataforma

Universidad Tecnológica de Jalisco, Ingeniería

GUADALAJARA, JALISCO, MÉXICO

Desarrollo y Gestión de Software

Certifications

PROLEX, TOEFL ITP

GUADALAJARA, JALISCO, MÉXICO

C1 Level with a total Score of 627 points